"Perfect Strangers"
"전혀 모르는 낯선 사람"
"(Kim Dong-wook)"
"(김동욱)"
"(Jin Gi Joo)"
"(진기주)"
"Perfect Strangers"
"전혀 모르는 낯선 사람"
Two nights before the teacher died, she suddenly disappeared
선생님이 돌아가시기 이틀 전, 갑자기 사라졌어요
Looks like someone is chasing her
누군가가 그녀를 쫓고 있는 것 같아
It's very close to the grocery store so be sure to come here.
식육점과 매우 가깝기 때문에 꼭 이곳으로 오세요.
"In the last episode..."
"마지막회에..."
Miss Li
미스 리
- Miss Li- No, not me!
- 미스 리- 아냐, 난 아니야!
Who looked at the teacher and ran away yesterday?
어제 선생님을 보고 도망간 사람은 누구였나요?
Who is the one?
그 사람은 누구입니까?
I think he's the one I've been waiting for
내 생각엔 그 사람이 내가 기다려온 사람인 것 같아
Then I can see the man in the blue hat again
그러면 파란 모자를 쓴 남자를 다시 볼 수 있어요
Ms. Li stayed in the cafe for 20 minutes...
리씨는 카페에 20분간 머물렀다..
the only person i met there
내가 거기서 만난 유일한 사람
But the guy I chased last night was wearing a blue hat
그런데 어젯밤에 내가 쫓던 그 남자는 파란 모자를 쓰고 있었어
That's why I plan to witness this for myself
그래서 내가 직접 목격할 생각이야
"Perfect Strangers Episode 6 Lie After Lie"
"완벽한 낯선 사람 6화 거짓말 뒤에 거짓말"
"Episode 6"
"에피소드 6"
Oh my god
맙소사
Do you know what time it is?
지금이 몇 시인지 아시나요?
OK...
좋아요...
You know what that feels like...
그게 어떤 느낌인지 아시죠...
Waiting for someone who goes out to meet a killer?
킬러를 만나러 나가는 사람을 기다리나요?
You said you just wanted to see his face , but you disappeared for three hours!
그 사람 얼굴만 보고 싶다고 하다가 3시간 동안 사라졌어요!
Oh my god, what is that?
맙소사, 그게 뭐야?
She was afraid that she would get hurt following him like last night
어젯밤처럼 그를 따라가다가 다칠까 두려웠던 그녀
- Are you hurt? - No
- 다쳤어요? - 아니요
I can't call the police or go out to find you...
경찰에 신고할 수도 없고 널 찾으러 나갈 수도 없어...
Because we live in stupid 1987 and I can't even call you
왜냐면 우리는 멍청한 1987년에 살고 있고 너한테 전화도 할 수 없으니까
I almost lost my mind
나는 거의 정신을 잃을 뻔했다
sorry
죄송합니다
Is the man in the blue hat here?
파란 모자를 쓴 남자가 여기 있나요?
OK...
좋아요...
who is he?
그는 누구입니까?
"Three hours ago"
"3시간 전"
“(Ping Pong Teahouse)”
“(핑퐁티하우스)”
your father...
아버지...
"Baek Hee-seop"
'백희섭'
Damn it
젠장
May 14, 1987
1987년 5월 14일
That day the first murder occurred
그날 첫 번째 살인이 일어났습니다.
The man who met the victim Lee Joo-young that day...
그날 피해자 이주영을 만난 남자..
Is it her father?
그녀의 아버지인가요?
If the man in the blue hat is the real culprit...
파란 모자를 쓴 남자가 진짜 범인이라면…
That means he even killed her mother
즉, 그는 심지어 그녀의 어머니를 죽였다는 뜻이다
So he even killed his wife
그래서 자기 아내까지 죽였어.
If I...
만약 내가...
I can't be biased
나는 편견을 가질 수 없다
I have to stay calm and objective
침착하고 객관적이어야 한다
Let's summarize
요약해보자
If everything remains the same...
모든 것이 그대로라면...
Li Zhuying was supposed to arrive seven minutes earlier than him
Li Zhuying은 자신보다 7분 일찍 도착하기 로 되어 있었습니다.
If nothing happens today...
오늘 아무 일도 일어나지 않는다면...
I want to go to a cafe after school
학교 끝나고 카페에 가고 싶어요
I want to have a cup of coffee alone...
혼자 커피 한잔 마시고 싶은데..
Finish the book you started
시작한 책을 끝내세요
I didn't plan on meeting anyone.
나는 누구도 만날 계획이 없었습니다.
But she ends up meeting someone she wasn't planning on meeting
하지만 그녀는 만날 계획이 없던 사람을 만나게 됩니다.
I don't want to talk about this
나는 이것에 대해 이야기하고 싶지 않다
The man in the blue hat "Baek Hee-seop"
파란모자를 쓴 남자 '백희섭'
For whatever reason, the two had a fight.
어떤 이유에서인지 둘은 싸웠다.
I told you to stay there!
내가 거기 있으라고 했잖아!
The only person who witnessed their fight was...
그들의 싸움을 목격한 유일한 사람은...
Owner of "Ping Pong Tea House"
'핑퐁찻집' 주인
where did you go?
어디 갔어?
welcome
환영
there are more people
사람이 더 많아요
I am coming
나는 온다
Oh my God, I'm sorry
맙소사, 미안해요
I'm late because I heard some crazy news on the way here
여기 오는 길에 이상한 소식을 들어서 늦었어요
Do you remember what happened at school this morning?
오늘 아침에 학교에서 무슨 일이 있었는지 기억하시나요?
Because of parameters?
매개변수 때문에?
Do you know why?
이유를 아시나요?
It turns out...
그것은 밝혀...
Said she was a communist
그 사람은 공산주의자라고 하더군요
Don't you watch the news?
뉴스를 안 보시나요?
These college students are crazy and come out to protest
이 대학생들은 미쳤고 항의하러 나왔다.
Do you remember that strange song...
그 이상한 노래를 기억하시나요?
Which song did you sing on your school trip?
수학여행 때 어떤 노래를 불렀나요?
This is the song people sang at the protests
시위에서 사람들이 불렀던 노래입니다.
I bet she wants to influence us too
분명 그 사람도 우리한테 영향을 주고 싶어할 것 같아
Isn't this terrible?
이건 끔찍하지 않나요?
- Yeah, it's scary - isn't it?
- 응, 무섭지 - 그렇지?
Oh my god, just thinking about it gives me goosebumps
맙소사, 생각만 해도 소름이 돋네
my parents...
내 부모님...
Because my friend did this
내 친구가 그랬으니까
how do you know?
어떻게 알아?
You said you pooped
똥쌌다고 했잖아
But I want to know why there is no smell
그런데 왜 냄새가 나지 않는지 알고 싶어요
Liu Fanling, haven't you finished speaking yet?
Liu Fanling, 아직 말 안 끝났나요?
Both
둘 다
I ate a lot today
오늘은 많이 먹었다
Look, I don't know what's going on...
봐봐, 무슨 일인지 모르겠어...
But something happened in our school
그런데 우리 학교에 무슨 일이 일어났어요
Police swarmed our school looking for teachers
경찰이 학교에 몰려들어 교사를 찾았습니다.
- Who are they looking for? - New parameters
- 그들은 누구를 찾고 있나요? - 새로운 매개변수
God, that idiot
맙소사, 그 바보야
The bathroom wasn't even cleaned
화장실은 청소도 안되어 있었는데
Damn, this disgusting thing
젠장, 이 역겨운 일이
"Let's use the toilet like we would in our own homes."
"화장실을 집에서처럼 사용하자."
Is this for new teachers?
이것은 새로운 교사를 위한 것입니까?
Did you steal it?
훔쳤나요?
will you tell me?
나한테 말해줄래?
What?
무엇?
Do...
하다...
Would you tell anyone about this ring?
이 반지에 대해 누구에게도 말해줄 수 있나요?
Did you steal it even though you knew it was wrong?
잘못된 줄 알면서도 훔쳤나요?
I stole someone else's stuff and hid it in the bathroom
남의 물건을 훔쳐서 화장실에 숨겼어요
If Sun-ae knew what she had done...
만약 순애가 자신이 무슨 짓을 했는지 알았다면...
"Sun Ai"?
"선 아이"?
How do you know my girlfriend's name?
내 여자친구 이름을 어떻게 아나요?
Have you ever thought about...
혹시 생각해 보셨나요...
How much harm would it cause her if she knew?
그녀가 알면 얼마나 해를 끼칠까요?
Don't do anything to embarrass yourself...
당황스러울 일은 하지 마세요...
in front of your girlfriend
네 여자친구 앞에서
every man should know
남자라면 누구나 알아야 할
Wait, "Hee-seob"
잠깐만요, "희섭씨"
wait
기다리다
OK
좋아요
I'll give it back to her
나는 그것을 그녀에게 돌려줄 것이다
I'll tell her I'm curious...
궁금하다고 말할게요...
I personally apologize to her
나는 개인적으로 그녀에게 사과한다
I'll give it back to her
나는 그것을 그녀에게 돌려줄 것이다
So give it back to me
그러니까 나한테 돌려줘
I mean
내 말은
Like I said, I don’t want to do anything…
아까 말했듯이 난 아무것도 하고 싶지 않아...
Might make me feel embarrassed in front of my girlfriend...
여자친구앞에서 부끄러워질수도..
In front of you, my friend
친구야 네 앞에서
I will keep it a secret
비밀로 할게요
I won't tell anyone about this
나는 이것에 대해 아무에게도 말하지 않을 것입니다
I'll pretend nothing happened
아무 일도 없었던 척 할게
But you must also keep your promise
하지만 약속도 지켜야 해
OK
좋아요
thank you my partner
고마워요 내 파트너
- "Hee-seop" - "Yoo-seop"
- "희섭" - "유섭"
welcome
환영
Be a good friend to my brother
내 동생에게 좋은 친구가 되어주세요
OK
좋아요
What's wrong?
뭐가 문제 야?
“(Ping Pong Teahouse)”
“(핑퐁티하우스)”
Baoling stole Li Zhuying's ring.
Baoling은 Li Zhuying의 반지를 훔쳤습니다.
Baek Hee-seop was the man in the blue hat who escaped on the bridge that night.
그날 밤 다리 위로 탈출한 파란 모자의 남자는 백희섭이었다 .
At that time, Baek Hee-seop walked out of the cafe with someone.
그 시각 백희섭은 누군가와 함께 카페를 나섰다.
And Liu Fanling...
그리고 류판링...
He was walking in the same direction as the victim
그는 피해자와 같은 방향으로 걷고 있었다
The path Lee Joo-young has traveled
이주영이 걸어온 길
“(Ping Pong Teahouse)”
“(핑퐁티하우스)”
"hotel"
"호텔"
hurry up!
서둘러요!
Are you kidding me now?
지금 장난하는 거야?
“Takamishu”?
"타카슈 히데"?
This is extremely unfair
이건 굉장히 불공평해요
On the day of the incident...
사건 당일...
I'm not even in Woojong-ri.
우종리에도 없어요.
At the time, I was living in a private boarding school far away from the city
당시 저는 도시에서 멀리 떨어진 사립 기숙학교에 살고 있었습니다.
My mother sent me there to focus on my studies
어머니는 공부에 집중하라고 나를 그곳으로 보냈어요
The school is in the middle of a mountain and there is no landline phone.
학교가 산속에 있어서 유선전화도 없습니다.
Do you want to die?
죽고 싶나요?
Why is he here?
그 사람은 왜 여기 있는 걸까요?
Your dear brother...
사랑하는 동생...
He's the one who asked
물어본 사람이 바로 그 사람이에요
Give it to me and let's end this
나한테 주고 이걸 끝내자
Why are you talking to me like this?
왜 나한테 이런 얘기를 하는 거야?
wait
기다리다
Is this your money?
이게 당신 돈인가요?
I probably got it from my mom's purse anyway.
아마 엄마 지갑에서 꺼낸 것 같아요.
Yes or no?
예 혹은 아니오?
"Mi Shu"
"미슈"
you are such a loser
넌 정말 패배자야
My mother kicked you out of the house
엄마가 널 집에서 쫓아냈어
Don't act like you're strong
강한 척하지 마세요
Hey...
여기요...
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
Come here, you...
이리 오세요, 당신은...
curse
저주
my arms...
내 팔...
you hurt my arm
너 내 팔을 다쳤어
I'm sorry, my future self, for saving a filthy scum like you!
미안해 미래의 나 너같은 더러운 놈을 구해서!
What should I do to you?
내가 당신을 어떻게 해야 합니까?
This is all because of you idiot!
이게 다 너 때문이야 이 바보야!
-It's your fault! - Are you OK?
-네 잘못이야! - 괜찮으세요?
Go to the nearest public phone and call the police
가장 가까운 공중전화로 가서 경찰에 신고하세요
I don't trust the police system...
경찰 시스템을 못 믿겠다...
But I should at least leave you a record
하지만 최소한 기록이라도 남겨야겠어
I'll make sure he pays for what he did this time
이번에는 그가 한 짓에 대한 대가를 치르게 해줄게
Gao Meishu, think about it carefully
가오메이슈, 잘 생각해보세요
I do not want...
하고 싶지 않다...
contact police
경찰에 연락하다
He has some money now
그 사람 지금 돈이 좀 있어
When he has had fun and feels better, he will return to boarding school
재미있고 기분이 나아지면 기숙학교로 돌아갈 것입니다.
that's what i need
그게 내가 필요한 거야
If he gets into trouble again...
만약 그 사람이 또 말썽을 피우면...
my mother will punish me
엄마가 나한테 벌을 주실 거야
so...
그래서...
I want this to stay between us
난 이게 우리 사이에 머물기를 원해
"Wozhuang Hotel"
"워좡 호텔"
These kids will never go home
이 아이들은 집에 절대 안 갈 거예요
This is the path Lee Joo Young took.
이주영이 걸어온 길이다.
perhaps...
아마도...
One of the boys I met tonight is the real culprit.
오늘 밤에 만난 소년 중 한 명이 진짜 범인입니다.
But I met...
그런데 만났는데...
All three suspects tonight
오늘밤 용의자 3명 모두
I will keep it a secret
비밀로 할게요
i won't tell anyone
난 아무한테도 말하지 않을 거야
"bathroom"
"화장실"
OK
좋아요
I'll give it back to her
나는 그것을 그녀에게 돌려줄 것이다
I will give it back to her and I will apologize to her personally
그 사람한테 돌려주고 개인적으로 사과할게.
I will never come to this neighborhood again
나는 다시는 이 동네에 오지 않을 것이다.
Are you happy now?
당신은 지금 행복합니까?
"direct road"
"직통 도로"
Everyone I met along the way...
길에서 만난 모든 사람들..
they are lying
그들은 거짓말을 하고 있어요
Why did they lie? Why on earth do they do this?
그들은 왜 거짓말을 했나요? 도대체 그들은 왜 이런 짓을 하는 걸까요?
Why are you so quiet?
너는 왜 이렇게 조용하니?
young man wearing blue hat
파란 모자를 쓴 청년
He might be the criminal who killed my mother
그 사람이 우리 엄마를 죽인 범인일지도 몰라
You saw him in the cafe, right?
그 사람 카페에서 봤지, 그렇지?
who is he? Do we know who he is?
그는 누구입니까? 그 사람이 누군지 알아요?
I can't see his face
나는 그 사람의 얼굴을 볼 수 없습니다
I lost it like last time
지난번처럼 잃어버렸어
It's my fault, I'm sorry
내 잘못이야, 미안해
i lied
나는 거짓말했다
You said you weren't hurt, but you were.
당신은 다치지 않았다고 말했지만 당신은 다쳤습니다.
You must be hurt every time your shirt touches it
셔츠가 닿을 때마다 다칠 텐데
it's not a big deal
별거 아니야
How is Miss Li?
미스 리(Miss Li)는 어떤가요?
She looks worried but she's fine
그녀는 걱정스러워 보이지만 괜찮아요
She was worried that the police might know about it and come here
경찰이 이 사실을 알고 여기로 올까 봐 걱정이 됐어요.
She said we'd be in trouble too
그녀는 우리도 곤란해질 거라고 했어
Don't worry
괜찮아요
No one can come here tonight
오늘 밤엔 아무도 여기에 올 수 없어
"Eunying"
"은잉"
If you want to knock on the door...
문을 두드리고 싶다면...
You shouldn't whisper and vice versa
속삭이거나 그 반대의 경우도 마찬가지입니다.
Don’t you have to choose one way?
한 가지 방법을 선택해야 하지 않나요?
I'm sorry for coming so late
너무 늦게 와서 미안해요
Is Yin Ying at home?
인영이 집에 있어?
Yanying, are you okay?
옌잉, 괜찮아?
Why might I not?
왜 안 될까요?
I heard all this from my father
나는 이 모든 것을 아버지에게서 들었다.
He said something terrible happened
끔찍한 일이 일어났다고 하더군요
Someone had a knife in the grocery store this morning
오늘 아침에 누군가 식료품점에서 칼을 가지고 있었습니다
you must be scared
넌 겁이 나겠구나
- Nothing important - Is this possible?
- 별거 없어요 - 이게 가능해요?
Incidentally...
그런데...
Are you going to let Eun-young sleep here tonight?
오늘 밤은 은영이를 여기서 자게 해줄 건가요?
with you?
너와 함께?
What?
무엇?
Well, I mean...
글쎄, 내 말은...
Can she stay with me for one night?
그녀가 나와 하룻밤 묵을 수 있을까요?
Well, that would be great
글쎄요, 그러면 좋을 것 같아요
I did not expect
나는 기대하지 않았다
you can let it go
넌 그걸 놔둬도 돼
No, it's okay, it's just a misunderstanding
아냐 괜찮아 그냥 오해일 뿐이야
Just go and take a rest...
그냥 가서 쉬어라...
Use this as an excuse to relax
이것을 긴장을 풀 핑계로 삼으십시오.
I came here after she died
나는 그녀가 죽은 후에 여기로 왔어요
Relax for at least one night
적어도 하룻밤은 휴식을 취하세요
In addition to your mother, this is also a good opportunity
엄마뿐만 아니라 이것도 좋은 기회야
Is my room a mess?
내 방이 엉망인가?
Although I arranged it
정리했지만
My mother always pats me on the back
엄마는 항상 내 등을 토닥여준다
She even threatened me that she would throw away all my stuff
심지어 내 물건을 다 버리겠다고 협박까지 하더군요
My mother is like this too
우리 엄마도 그러셔요
Really?
정말?
Moms, do you have any questions?
엄마들, 궁금한 점이 있나요?
I would never do that to my daughter
나는 내 딸에게 절대 그런 짓을 하지 않을 것이다
I'm going to take a shower. You're welcome.
샤워하고 갈게요 천만에요.
Okay, let's take a shower
알았어, 샤워하자
Both
둘 다
Why should he hide it?
왜 숨겨야합니까?
Who are you calling...
누구한테 전화하는 거야...
this late?
이렇게 늦게?
You said you've been worried all day
하루종일 고민했다고 했잖아
let me check
내가 체크해 볼게
"Wu Zong Restaurant"
"우종 레스토랑"
Do I really need to check?
꼭 확인해야 하나요?
- It's messy enough here - "The one I miss"
- 여기도 충분히 지저분해요 - "그리운 사람"
well done!
잘하셨어요!
"I miss her"
"그녀가 그리워요"
Yes, everyone here
네, 여기 계신 분들 모두
- President Yoon - Wait
- 윤 총장 - 잠깐만요
what are you doing here? now you
여기서 뭐하는거야? 이제 당신은
yes ok
응 알았어
Hold on
기다리다
- Come on - Everyone applaud!
- 어서 - 모두 박수를 쳐주세요!
OK
좋아요
President Yoon wants to sing, let’s help him sing
윤 총장이 노래하고 싶어, 노래를 도와주자
No, I can't sing
아니요, 노래를 못해요
I only wish the police officers happiness...
경찰관님들의 행복을 빕니다..
Those who work tirelessly day and night
밤낮 가리지 않고 일하는 분들
Keep Houzongli away from crime
Houzongli를 범죄로부터 멀리 유지하십시오
that's all i need to hear
그게 내가 듣고 싶은 전부야
Applaud President Yoon!
윤 총장에게 박수를 보내드립니다!
As I said before...
내가 전에 말했듯이...
Today's reception is for the peace of our city
오늘의 리셉션은 우리 도시의 평화를 위한 것입니다
Don't even think about going home tonight
오늘 밤 집에 갈 생각도 하지 마
Eat and drink as much as you want
원하는 만큼 먹고 마시세요
- OK! - let's go!
- 좋아요! - 갑시다!
Cheers to the happiness and prosperity of Hojongri Police!
호종리경찰의 행복과 번영을 응원합니다!
- cheers!
- 건배!
Oh my god
맙소사
Grill more meat too
고기도 더 굽고
Can we drink more?
더 마셔도 될까요?
what have you done?
당신은 무엇을 했나요?
As a principal, how could he not know that there would be a person with a criminal record as our teacher?
교장으로서 어떻게 우리 선생님으로서 전과자가 있을 줄을 몰랐을 수 있겠습니까 ?
she tried to help me
그녀는 나를 도우려고 했어요
I make sure everyone finishes what they start
나는 모두가 시작한 일을 끝내도록 한다
So don't worry about this
그러니 이것에 대해 걱정하지 마세요
Yes, as we discussed before...
네, 앞서 논의했듯이...
Please keep everyone there until sunrise
해가 뜰 때까지 모두 그곳에 머물도록 해주세요.
I'll get you a drink, good job
내가 한잔 사줄게, 수고했어
you sit
당신은 앉아
Can't you see we're cleaning up the mess you made after you made a mess in the school?
당신이 학교를 엉망으로 만든 후에 우리가 당신이 만든 엉망진창을 청소하고 있는 것을 볼 수 없습니까 ?
move
이동하다
President Kim said he felt very embarrassed facing Chairman Yoon.
김 대통령은 윤 위원장을 만나 매우 당황스럽다고 말했다.
To be honest, there are no clear charges against him
솔직히 말해서 그에 대한 명확한 혐의는 없습니다.
tell me the truth
나에게 진실을 말해
I just want to blame the protesters from Seoul for improving your image
나는 단지 당신의 이미지를 개선한 것에 대해 서울에서 온 시위대를 비난하고 싶을 뿐입니다.
I say if you look suspicious it's your fault
난 네가 의심스러워 보이면 그건 네 잘못이라고 해
You also said that if you were trying to manipulate someone you could easily make up some crime
당신은 또한 누군가를 조종하려고 하면 쉽게 범죄를 저지를 수 있다고 말했습니다.
To improve my image?
내 이미지를 개선하기 위해?
I wonder who needs to do this
누가 이런 일을 해야 하는지 궁금해요
You bastard, how dare you?
이 개자식아, 어떻게 감히?
- Stay away from me - Are you crazy?
- 나에게서 멀리 떨어져 - 너 미쳤어?
I have to pick up my kids
아이들을 데리러 가야 해요
- Oh my God, you idiot. - For you.
- 맙소사, 이 바보야 - 당신을 위해서요
What do you two think you're doing?
둘이 뭐하고 있는 것 같아?
I started to calm down
나는 진정하기 시작했다
-Are you really doing this? - sorry
- 정말 이러는 건가요? - 죄송합니다
- Dong -sik- Yes
- 동식 - 네
Where are Young Woo and Young Soon? Isn't she at home?
영우와 영순은 어디에 있나요? 그 사람 집에 없나요?
My wife went to visit her parents...
아내가 부모님을 만나러 갔습니다..
To take care of my sick father
아픈 아버지를 간호하기 위해
OK
좋아요
I left the children at home by the persimmon tree.
나는 아이들을 집 감나무 옆에 남겨 두었습니다.
Understood
이해했다
Especially Baek Dong-sik
특히 백동식
Bring all the police to our school today
오늘 경찰을 모두 우리 학교로 데려오세요
He turned the whole place upside down
그는 모든 곳을 뒤집어 놓았습니다
We never know when or what he will do next
그가 다음에 언제, 무엇을 할지 우리는 결코 알 수 없습니다
it's not a big problem
그건 큰 문제가 아니야
Look at the current time
현재 시간을 봐
let them spend the night there
거기서 밤을 보내도록 해주세요
Sit down, everyone, sit down
모두들 앉으세요
your kids will love it
당신의 아이들은 그것을 좋아할 것입니다
The boss's grandson is about the same age as your child, right?
사장님의 손자가 당신 아이와 나이가 거의 같죠?
- Am I right? - OK
- 내 말이 맞나요? - 좋아요
I'll also call the lady of the house
나도 그 집 아줌마한테 전화할게
Don't worry about that
그건 걱정하지 마세요
Until sunrise...
일출까지...
Okay, get me a drink
알았어, 나한테 한잔 줘
Just stay here
그냥 여기 있어
- Okay - let's go
- 알았어 - 가자
President Yoon, I deeply apologize for causing confusion.
윤 총장님, 혼란을 끼쳐드려 깊이 사과드립니다.
It's okay, drink it
괜찮아요 마셔요
Everyone, get ready to sing for President Yoon!
여러분, 윤총장을 위해 노래할 준비를 하세요!
- Oh my god - Yes!
- 맙소사 - 그래!
one two three four
하나 둘 셋 넷
Is something bothering you?
뭔가 괴로운 일이 있나요?
I noticed you never sleep
나는 당신이 잠을 자지 않는다는 것을 알았습니다
Are you awake?
깨어있나요?
All this is...
이 모든 것은...
I can't get it out of my head
머리에서 지울 수 없어
what is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
What bothers you so much that you can't sleep?
무엇이 당신을 그렇게 괴롭혀 잠을 이루지 못합니까?
"Baek Hee-seop"
'백희섭'
What? So fast?
무엇? 그렇게 빠르나요?
Listen, you said you still have a boyfriend
들어봐, 아직도 남자친구가 있다고 했잖아
I'm the worst
내가 최악이야
what should I do?
어떻게 해야 합니까?
God this gives me a headache
맙소사, 이거 때문에 머리가 아프네
I thought I could relax for a night
하룻밤은 쉬어도 될 것 같았는데
listen
듣다
Hee-seop and I have only known each other for a short time.
희섭씨와 저는 서로 알고 지낸 기간이 짧습니다.
He doesn't even know you that well
그 사람은 당신을 잘 알지도 못해요
That's why I asked him
그래서 내가 그 사람한테 물어봤지
When I met him at Pong Pong Café
퐁퐁카페에서 만났을 때
Incidentally...
그런데...
Why do you like me so much?
왜 나를 그렇게 좋아합니까?
you don't know me very well
당신은 나를 잘 몰라요
You were transferred a few days ago...
며칠전에 이적되셨는데요..
And you don't even know who I am
그리고 넌 내가 누군지도 모르지
Why might I not know you?
나는 왜 당신을 모를 수 있습니까?
As soon as I met you, I discovered your essence
너를 만나자마자 너의 본질을 발견했어
What kind of girl am I?
나는 어떤 여자인가요?
a great girl
훌륭한 소녀
Too...
도...
you have your own world
너는 너만의 세계를 가지고 있어
When I first met you...
처음 만났을 때...
In that cabin...
그 오두막에서...
You are listening to your favorite song on the radio
당신은 라디오에서 당신이 가장 좋아하는 노래를 듣고 있습니다
Very focused on writing...
글쓰기에 집중도 많이 하시고..
That you didn't even notice me standing there
내가 거기 서 있는 것도 당신이 눈치채지 못했다는 걸요
I'm too busy in the world I've created
내가 만든 세상에서 난 너무 바빠
you don't know how beautiful you look
당신은 당신이 얼마나 아름다운지 몰라요
And that cabin...
그리고 그 오두막은...
She shines like a star, just because you are here
그녀는 별처럼 빛난다, 당신이 있기 때문에
"I don't care about anything in this world"
"나는 이 세상 어떤 것에도 관심이 없어요"
you just smile alone
넌 그냥 혼자 웃어
In fact...
사실은...
I've never met anyone as good as you
난 너만큼 좋은 사람을 만난 적이 없어
He shines like a star in front of me
내 앞에선 별처럼 빛나네
What he told me...
그 사람이 나한테 한 말은...
And the expression on his face when he spoke...
그리고 말할때 표정이..
in his low, hesitant voice
그의 낮고 주저하는 목소리로
everything is shiny
모든 것이 반짝인다
"A moment that never ends"
"끝나지 않는 순간"
"small door"
"작은 문"
"Message 25"
"메시지 25"
"You know what, Y?"
"그거 알아요, Y?"
"For a moment..."
"잠시 동안..."
"It never ends"
"결코 끝나지 않아"
I think of those beautiful words he said to me that day
그 날 그 사람이 나에게 했던 아름다운 말이 생각난다
repeatedly
자꾸
Get out, if you want to keep doing this...
나가세요, 계속 이럴거면..
Spend the rest of your life doing this
남은 인생을 이 일을 하면서 보내세요
Whatever future darkness may befall me...
미래의 어떤 어둠이 나에게 닥치더라도...
If you can keep these shining moments...
빛나는 이 순간을 간직할 수 있다면...
I thought nothing in the world could scare me
세상의 어떤 것도 나를 놀라게 할 수 없다고 생각했어요
It only took him a moment to see my world
그 사람이 내 세상을 보는 데는 시간이 좀 걸렸을 뿐이야
I want to know what his world is like
그의 세계가 어떤지 알고 싶다
I'm always curious...
항상 궁금해요...
about the shape of his world
그의 세계의 형태에 대해
The man in my mother’s novel…
엄마 소설 속 그 남자..
he is...
그는...
"Baek Hee-seop"
'백희섭'
What?
무엇?
Are you going to bed?
자러 갈 건가요?
what should I do?
어떻게 해야 합니까?
"Baek Hee-seop"
'백희섭'
I'm here because I want to give something back to her
나는 그녀에게 뭔가를 돌려주고 싶어서 여기에 왔어요
for new teachers
새로운 교사를 위해
I'm going out...
내가 외출 해요...
walk a little
조금 걷다
He is one of the three suspects
그는 세 명의 용의자 중 한 명이다
And the mysterious man in the blue hat
그리고 파란 모자를 쓴 신비한 남자
His position is consistent with that of Lee Joo Young.
그의 입장은 이주영의 입장과 일치한다.
So far, he's the prime suspect
현재까지 그가 유력 용의자다.
but...
하지만...
If he told Liu Fanling to return the ring, why did he kill her?
그가 Liu Fanling에게 반지를 돌려달라고 말했다면 왜 그녀를 죽였습니까?
some things don't make sense
어떤 것들은 말이 안 돼요
Or am I hoping for something similar?
아니면 비슷한 것을 바라는 걸까요?
"Wozhuang Hotel"
"워좡 호텔"
I brought all my important possessions
중요한 물건은 다 가져왔어
- Let's go. - Okay.
- 가자 - 알았어
"From Hou Zhongli to Yuanzu"
"허우중리에서 원주까지"
curse
저주
How did I get involved with that dangerous neighbor?
나는 어떻게 그 위험한 이웃과 연루되었습니까?
There will be no danger if you leave the village
마을을 벗어나면 위험하지 않아요
But just to make sure...
하지만 확실히 하기 위해...
Call me as soon as you get to your friend's house
친구 집에 도착하자마자 전화해
- The landline number is... - I know.
- 유선 전화번호는... - 알아요.
You gave me your number as soon as I got here.
내가 여기에 오자마자 당신은 나에게 당신의 번호를 주었습니다.
I know it doesn't make sense...
말도 안 된다는 걸 알아요...
But it seems you...
하지만 당신은 ...
You came here just to save me
당신은 단지 나를 구하기 위해 여기에 왔어요
It's like you knew I'd be here and you were waiting for me
마치 내가 여기 있을 줄 알고 나를 기다리고 있었던 것 같군요
It's like you thought...
당신이 생각한 것과 같습니다 ...
Helped me in some way for a long time
오랫동안 어떤 식으로든 도움이 됐어요
it's out of the question
그건 말도 안 돼
correct
옳은
I know it's impossible but you helped me like you really did it
불가능하다는 걸 알지만 정말 그랬던 것처럼 도와줬어
Thanks
감사해요
Laura, your presence...
로라, 당신의 존재는...
i don't know what will happen to me
나에게 무슨 일이 일어날지 모르겠어요
Thank you so much
매우 감사합니다
"Youzong Grocery Store"
"유종 식료품점"
Help yourself
알아서 드세요
Don't lose him again
다시는 그 사람을 잃지 마세요
I wish you a happy life...
행복한 삶을 기원합니다...
Enjoy a healthy and long life until old age
노년까지 건강하고 오래오래 누리세요
The same to you
너도 마찬가지야
The bus is coming
버스가 온다
give yourself to me
너 자신을 나에게 줘
God this is so annoying
맙소사 이거 너무 짜증나
Has the bus arrived?
버스가 도착했나요?
Hey!
여기요!
curse
저주
for your own good
당신 자신의 이익을 위해
You fool, you!
바보야, 너!
you bastard
이 새끼야
When I was under the bridge that night, she secretly sent me signals to help her
그날 밤 내가 다리 아래에 있었을 때 그녀는 몰래 나에게 그녀를 도우라는 신호를 보냈습니다.
How dare you let the police help protesters?
어떻게 감히 경찰이 시위대를 돕게 놔두나요?
When I realized what I had done...
내가 무슨 짓을 했는지 깨달았을 때...
I thought you were just a forgetful teacher
난 당신이 단지 건망증이 있는 선생님인줄 알았는데
Are you one of them?
당신도 그들 중 하나인가요?
is that so?
그렇습니까?
How much did you drink?
얼마나 마셨나요?
"one of them"?
"그들 중 하나"?
I was just passing by there
난 그냥 그 곳을 지나가던 중이었어
Is it correct?
맞나요?
I'll find the truth when I start looking
진실을 찾기 시작하면 진실을 찾을 수 있을 거예요
Let's have this conversation at the center, shall we?
센터에서 이런 대화를 나눠볼까요?
Why did you take me away when I didn't do anything?
내가 아무 짓도 안 했는데 왜 나를 데리고 갔나요?
Stop talking and come with me, you bastard
그만 얘기하고 나랑 같이 가 이 새끼야
OMG
어머나
Oh my god, how could this happen?
맙소사, 어떻게 이런 일이 일어날 수 있지?
- Hey - Yeah
- 안녕 - 응
what happened? Is there a fire?
무슨 일이에요? 불이 났나요?
A fire broke out in the house next to the persimmon tree.
감나무 옆 집에 불이 났습니다.
What? Where?
무엇? 어디?
The house next to the persimmon tree where the boy lives with his grandmother
소년이 할머니와 함께 살고 있는 감나무 옆집
God, I hope they're okay. what should we do?
맙소사, 그들이 괜찮기를 바랍니다. 우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
On May 15, a fire accident occurred
5월 15일 화재사고가 발생했습니다.
no one died
아무도 죽지 않았어
My two children are in that house.
내 두 아이가 그 집에 있어요.
what are you saying? There should only be two people inside
당신이 무슨 말을하는거야? 안에는 2명만 있어야 해요
I had to pick them up last night
어젯밤에 그것들을 데리러 가야 했어
but I can not
하지만 나는 못해
Both
둘 다
God no
맙소사 안돼
Honey, what are we going to do, Dong-sik?
여보, 우리 뭐할까 동식아?
- "Young Woo" - None
- "영우" - 없음
No, oh my god
아니, 맙소사
Yingyu, Yingshun!
잉규, 잉슌!
"Youngwoo!"
"영우!"
- there - she's here
- 거기 - 그녀는 여기 있어요
- Yingshun, it's your father. - Your father is here.
- 잉슌, 네 아버지야 - 네 아버지가 오셨어
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
"Xiao Sun!"
"샤오순!"
Sorry, Yang Shun.
미안해요, 양순 씨.
- Get the old lady out - Madam
- 노부인을 내보내세요 - 부인
Where are the rest of the kids?
나머지 아이들은 어디에 있나요?
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
I think I got my grandson out of there
내 생각엔 손자를 거기서 데리고 나온 것 같아
Oh my god, the house is falling down.
맙소사, 집이 무너지고 있어요.
- Oh my God - What are we going to do?
- 맙소사 - 우리는 무엇을 할 건가요?
"Youngwoo!"
"영우!"
- "Yang Yu"!
- "양유"!
Can you stop them from going out before sunrise?
해가 뜨기 전에 그들이 밖으로 나가는 것을 막을 수 있나요 ?
Especially Baek Dong-sik
특히 백동식
Bring all the police to our school today...
오늘 경찰을 모두 우리 학교로 데려오세요...
He turned the whole place upside down
그는 모든 곳을 뒤집어 놓았습니다
I should have picked them up yesterday
어제 샀어야 했는데
but I can not
하지만 나는 못해
"Youngwoo!"
"영우!"
God he's so hot
맙소사 그 사람 너무 섹시해
Detective Parker, here we come!
파커 형사님, 왔어요!
- "Yang Yu"! - here
- "양유"! - 여기
Take him out quickly
그 사람 빨리 데리고 나가
"Youngwoo!"
"영우!"
Come on, Yongwoo
자, 용우야
Yongyu, stay with me
용규야 내 옆에 있어줘
"Xiao Wu"
"샤오우"
Yongyu, are you okay?
용규야, 괜찮아?
I'm very sorry
나는 매우 미안 해요
- Thank God - That's good
- 하느님 감사합니다 - 좋아요
-His father saved him . -You are wonderful
- 그의 아버지가 그를 구해줬어요 . - 당신은 훌륭해요
- Very close - Very good
- 아주 가깝다 - 아주 좋다
"Houzongli Fire Brigade"
"호우종리 소방대"
“Hiko”
“희자”
uncle dongshik
동식 삼촌
Your teacher must go to the hospital
선생님은 병원에 가셔야 해요
excuse me?
실례합니다?
you were seriously injured
당신은 심각한 부상을 입었습니다
Let's go to the hospital
병원에 가자
what are you waiting for? Let's leave right away
무엇을 기다리고 있나요? 당장 떠나자
"In case of fire, please call emergency number 119"
"화재 발생시 긴급전화 119로 연락주세요"
What did I do to keep Lee Joo Young safe...
나는 이주영을 안전하게 지키기 위해 무엇을 했는지...
Create another variable...
다른 변수를 생성하세요...
This variable creates another situation
이 변수는 또 다른 상황을 만듭니다
I saved a man who might have died...
죽을지도 모르는 사람을 구했는데..
But on the other hand, I almost created a person who should have lived...
하지만 한편으로는 살아야 할 사람을 만들 뻔했는데…
he died
그는 죽었다
it's somewhere around here
이 근처 어딘가에 있어
Did you lose Miss Li...
미스 리를 잃었나요...
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
not much
별로
Did you and your mother have a good time?
당신과 당신의 어머니는 즐거운 시간을 보냈나요?
OK
좋아요
Why are you carrying this?
이걸 왜 들고 다니나요?
i think i can figure it out
내 생각엔 내가 알아낼 수 있을 것 같아
- Find out what? - The identity of the man in the blue hat
- 뭘 알아? - 파란 모자를 쓴 남자의 정체
Answer...
답변...
Maybe in this text
어쩌면 이 글에서
A novel is not a report...
소설은 보고서가 아니다...
Although it is based on a true story...
실화를 바탕으로 한 작품이긴 하지만..
This does not mean that real names were used
그렇다고 실명을 사용했다는 뜻은 아니다.
At first I thought Gao Meishi was not writing about a man wearing a blue hat.
처음에 나는 Gao Meishi가 파란 모자를 쓴 남자에 대해 글을 쓰고 있는 것이 아니라고 생각했습니다.
But then I remembered that there was a similar sentence
그런데 비슷한 문장이 있었던 게 생각났어요
"Blue Headed Man"
"푸른 머리의 남자"
all the time...
항상...
I thought it meant he had blue hair
파란머리인줄 알았는데
In the end what happened?
결국 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Do I have to tell you everything?
내가 당신에게 모든 것을 말해야 합니까?
Do I have to share every little detail of what's going on here?
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지에 대한 모든 작은 세부 사항을 공유해야 합니까 ?
And you?
당신은요?
Are we that close?
우리 그렇게 친해?
You know that, right?
그거 알지?
blue hat
파란 모자
you're not even curious
넌 궁금하지도 않잖아
You know who he is, don't you?
그 사람이 누군지 아시죠?
You didn't waste it in a cafe
카페에서 낭비한 게 아니잖아
You don't need to tell me...
나한테 말할 필요는 없어...
But there is a reason why you hid it from me. what is it then?
그런데 나한테 숨긴 이유가 있다. 그럼 뭐야?
I think you misunderstood something
내 생각엔 당신이 뭔가를 오해한 것 같아요
think carefully
잘 생각 해봐
If you're here to hide something...
뭔가 숨기려고 여기 왔다면...
Why should I go to great lengths to catch criminals?
왜 범인을 잡기 위해 많은 노력을 기울여야 합니까 ?
Because I feel sorry for the victim?
피해자가 안타깝기 때문에?
The world is full of tragedies like this
세상은 이런 비극으로 가득 차 있다
I don't have time to save all these people
이 사람들을 다 구해줄 시간이 없어
So what is the reason?
그렇다면 이유는 무엇입니까?
I am also a victim
나도 피해자다
fifth victim
다섯 번째 희생자
I will die like your mother in the future
나도 앞으로는 네 엄마처럼 죽을 거야
Because the real culprit hasn't been caught yet
아직 진짜 범인이 잡히지 않았기 때문에
You came here to save my life.
당신은 내 생명을 구하기 위해 여기에 왔습니다.
I transcribed every newspaper report, news broadcast, and case file…
신문보도, 뉴스방송, 사건파일까지 다 전사했는데 …
Associated with this village since 1987...
1987년부터 이 마을과 인연을 맺었습니다.
to my head
내 머리에
But everything could be in vain because of one variable
하지만 변수 하나 때문에 모든 것이 헛수고가 될 수도 있다
That alone makes me feel like my head is going to explode.
그것만으로도 머리가 터질 것 같은 느낌이 듭니다.
But you know what?
하지만 그거 알아요?
Do you know who the biggest variable is?
가장 큰 변수가 누구인지 아시나요?
Is this why you sent me to be with my mom last night?
그래서 어젯밤에 엄마랑 같이 있으라고 나를 보낸 거야?
"Don't even wonder about the variables."
"변수에 대해 궁금해하지 마세요."
"Don't get in my way"
"내 앞을 가로막지 마세요"
"Don't interfere"
"방해하지 마세요"
Is this what you want to say?
이것이 당신이 말하고 싶은 것입니까?
Sorry, but I can't
미안하지만 난 못해
Now that I've come this far...
이제 여기까지 왔으니...
I don't want to stand idly by like a fool
바보처럼 멍하니 서 있기는 싫어
If you don't want to tell me that's your business
나한테 말하고 싶지 않다면 그건 네 일이야
I'll find out for myself
내가 직접 알아볼게요
I feel uncomfortable
나는 불편하다
What if Fan Ling cries and becomes attached to me?
판링이 울면서 나에게 애착을 갖게 되면 어쩌지?
He said I'm the only one in his life
그는 그의 인생에서 내가 유일한 사람이라고 말했어
What's your job?
당신의 직업은 무엇입니까?
"Baek Eun-young"
"백은영"
"The afternoon the first victim's body was discovered..."
"첫 번째 피해자 시신이 발견된 그날 오후…"
"Some people started acting strange."
"몇몇 사람들이 이상하게 행동하기 시작했어요."
"The blue-haired man..."
"파란 머리 남자..."
"He always seemed to stand between the sun and the moon."
"그는 항상 해와 달 사이에 서 있는 것 같았어요."
"The man wearing glasses..."
"안경 쓴 남자.."
"He spent a long time in the third toilet."
"그는 세 번째 화장실에서 오랜 시간을 보냈습니다."
"The man who lost his memory..."
"기억을 잃은 남자..."
"He was lying under the bridge and they didn't know who he was."
"그는 다리 밑에 누워 있었는데 그들은 그가 누구인지 몰랐습니다."
"The blue-haired man stood between the sun and the moon for what seemed like forever."
"파란 머리의 남자는 영원할 것 같았던 태양과 달 사이에 서 있었습니다."
Li Zhuying was found dead on this day
이날 리주잉이 숨진 채 발견됐다.
So this part is about the current era
그래서 이 부분은 현 시대에 관한 것입니다.
If "the man with the blue head" really means the man with the blue hat...
"파란 머리 남자"가 정말로 파란 모자를 쓴 남자를 의미한다면...
"Sun and Moon"
"해와 달"
Where would it be "between the sun and the moon"?
"해와 달 사이"는 어디일까요?
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
What's this? scared me
이건 뭐죠? 날 무섭게했다
Go see Liu Fanling
류판링 보러가기
you have to deal with it one way or another
어떤 식으로든 처리해야 해
Ok, i will
알았어, 그럴게
BTW, don’t hang out with the guy who wrote this
그런데, 이 글 쓴 사람이랑 어울리지 마세요
I do not like it
나는 그것을 좋아하지 않는다
How do you know I didn't write this?
내가 이 글을 쓰지 않았다는 것을 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Are you a dummy?
당신은 더미입니까?
It is impossible for what you write not to be understood
당신이 쓴 내용이 이해되지 않는 것은 불가능합니다
The author should know everything...
글쓴이가 다 알아야 할텐데...
Because every word of his has been carefully chosen
그의 말 한 마디 한 마디가 신중하게 선택되었기 때문에
See you later
나중에 봐요
In 30 years you won't know anything I wrote
30년 뒤에는 내가 쓴 글을 당신은 아무것도 모르실 거예요
"Hey, Jun!"
"야, 준!"
- "Hey Jun!" - Can I strangle you?
- "야 준!" - 목을 조여도 될까요?
wait
기다리다
"First crime, second crime"
"첫 번째 범죄, 두 번째 범죄"
"The First Murder"
"첫 번째 살인"
"Investigation Report"
"조사 보고서"
I heard that Mr. Yin was injured
음씨가 부상을 입었다고 들었는데
If you need help please let me know
도움이 필요하면 알려주세요.
Because I'm still grateful for what I did.
왜냐하면 나는 내가 한 일에 대해 아직도 감사하고 있기 때문이다.
if...
만약에...
What happened to Gao Minxiu made you happy.
가오민슈에게 일어난 일이 당신을 행복하게 만들었습니다.
"The blue-haired man stood between the sun and the moon for what seemed like forever."
"파란 머리의 남자는 영원할 것 같았던 태양과 달 사이에 서 있었습니다."
If there is such a sentence...
그런 문장이 있다면..
What does "between the sun and the moon" mean?
"해와 달 사이"은(는) 무슨 뜻인가요?
how could I know?
내가 어떻게 알아?
I don't need to ask her
그녀에게 물어볼 필요는 없어
Isn't that the name of the record store?
그거 레코드 가게 이름 아닌가요?
"Record Store (Sun and Moon)"
"레코드 가게(해와 달)"
"sun"
"해"
"Guitar Lesson"
"기타 레슨"
"Record Store (Sun and Moon)"
"레코드 가게(해와 달)"
Do you know what time it is?
지금이 몇 시인지 아시나요?
if...
만약에...
You know that feeling when you hear someone waiting after school early?
학교가 끝나고 누군가가 일찍 기다리는 소리를 들었을 때 그 느낌을 아시나요?
Because we live in the stupid year of 1987…
우리는 어리석은 1987년에 살고 있기 때문에…
I can't even reach you
난 너에게 닿을 수도 없어
sorry
죄송합니다
I know I have to tell you...
말해야 한다는 걸 알아요...
But I hid the truth from you
하지만 난 너에게 진실을 숨겼어
But I didn't send you with your mother to get rid of you or anything like that.
그러나 나는 너를 없애 거나 그런 일을 하려고 너를 네 어머니와 함께 보낸 것이 아니다.
I know
알아요
The man in the blue hat is...
파란 모자를 쓴 남자는...
I know too
나도 알아
I saw it with my own eyes
나는 그것을 내 눈으로 보았다.
I also think I know why you had no choice but to hide the truth from me
너도 나한테 진실을 숨길 수밖에 없었던 이유를 알 것 같아
Because we are a family
우리는 가족이니까
He is just one of the suspects
그 사람은 용의자 중 한 명일 뿐이야
I actually don't like him very much...
사실 나 그 사람 별로 안 좋아하는데...
But I didn't expect him to be so cruel
하지만 그 사람이 그렇게 잔인할 줄 은 몰랐어요
my father loves him very much
우리 아버지는 그를 매우 사랑해요
Even more than he loves us
그 사람이 우리를 사랑하는 것보다 훨씬 더
excuse me?
실례합니다?
What?
무엇?
I mean...
내 말은...
Who are you talking about now?
지금 누구에 대해 이야기하고 있습니까?
I thought we were talking about the man in the blue hat
파란 모자를 쓴 남자에 대해 이야기하고 있는 줄 알았는데
Exactly
정확히
Why does Baek Hee-seop love himself so much?
백희섭은 왜 그토록 자신을 사랑하는가?
Are you saying the man in the blue hat is my father?
파란 모자를 쓴 남자가 내 아버지라는 겁니까?
So who did you see?
그럼 누구를 보셨나요?
"Record Store (Sun and Moon)"
"레코드 가게(해와 달)"
I saw my uncle
삼촌을 봤어요
"Bai Ruxie"
"바이 럭시"
Baek Yeo-seop isn’t even a suspect…
백여섭은 피의자도 아닌데…
He wasn't there last night
그 사람 어젯밤엔 거기 없었어
Everything makes sense now
이제 모든 것이 이해가 됩니다.
"(pingpong)"
"(탁구)"
"in conclusion"
"결론적으로"
"Yo Subbu"
"요 서브부"
what are you doing here? It's not even the weekend
여기서 뭐하는거야? 주말도 아닌데
I was supposed to meet someone here but I don't think he showed up
여기서 누군가를 만나기로 했는데 그 사람이 나타나지 않은 것 같아요
- And you? -I'm also here to meet someone.
- 당신은요? -나도 누굴 만나러 왔어요.
- Do you want to come with me? - It's okay, it's crowded inside.
- 나와 함께 갈래? -괜찮아요. 안에 사람이 많아요.
If you finish soon, I'll wait for you outside
빨리 끝나면 밖에서 기다릴게
- Can you? - certainly
- 할 수 있나요? - 틀림없이
i want it
나는 그것을 원한다
OMG your hat is so cool
으아 모자 너무 멋지다
for you
당신을 위한
let me see
좀 보자
Oh my gosh, it suits you so well.
맙소사, 정말 잘 어울리네요.
It looks better on me, doesn't it?
나한테는 그게 더 잘 어울리는 것 같죠?
-Don't be late- Okay, Yoo Seob.
-늦지 마세요- 알았어, 유섭.
"Perfect Strangers"
"전혀 모르는 낯선 사람"
These files do not contain any information about Baek You Sub
이 파일에는 백유섭에 대한 어떠한 정보도 포함되어 있지 않습니다.
No one knows Baek You-seop better than me
나만큼 백유섭을 잘 아는 사람은 없어
I'll provide you with everything you need
나는 당신에게 필요한 모든 것을 제공할 것입니다
If Baek Yeo-seop is the culprit...
백여섭이 범인이라면…
We'll see him again tomorrow night...
내일 밤에 다시 만나자...
Because he had to kill the second victim
두 번째 희생자를 죽여야 했기 때문에
Where is he?
그는 어디에 있나요?
- We're looking everywhere - This isn't going to happen anytime soon
- 우리는 모든 곳을 찾고 있습니다 . - 이런 일은 곧 일어나지 않을 것입니다
welcome
환영
"Perfect Strangers"
"전혀 모르는 낯선 사람"